Let's check out these two functions.
دعونا نتحقق من هاتين الدالتين.
First we have "callAndAdd",
فالدالة الأولى لدينا هي "callAndAdd"،
which takes in two arguments: the first one being a single number,
والتي تضم وسيطتين: الأولى رقم فردي،
and the second one being a callback function.
والثانية دالة استدعاء.
The other function over here is "returnsThree",
والدالة الثانية هنا هي "returnsThree"،
which actually doesn't take in any arguments but just returns simply the number three.
والتي لا تضم في الواقع أي وسيطات، ولكنها تقوم فقط بإرجاع الرقم ثلاثة ببساطة.
Let's go ahead and invoke "callAndAdd",
فهيا نتابع ونستدعي الدالة "callAndAdd"،
pass it a number,
ونمرر لها رقمًا،
and also pass in the "returnsThree" function into it as a callback.
ونمرر الدالة "returnsThree" كذلك إليها على أنها دالة استدعاء.
Great.
رائع.
So invoking the "callAndAdd" function and passing a
إذن استدعاء الدالة "callAndAdd" وتمرير
two and the callback function returns three,
الرقم اثنين ودالة الاستدعاء "returns three"،
gives us an output of five.
يعطينا الناتج خمسة.
Let's kind of see what's going on.
دعونا نرى ما يحدث نوعًا ما.
So code execution actually moves into the function "callAndAdd".
إذن ينتقل تنفيذ الكود بالفعل إلى الدالة "callAndAdd".
The end variable stored the number two that we passed in,
ويخزن المتغير النهائي الرقم اثنين الذي قمنا بتمريره،
and the callback function variable stores the returns three function that we passed in;
ويخزن متغير دالة الاستدعاء الدالة "returns three" التي قمنا بتمريرها؛
"callAndAdd" goes ahead and invokes the "returnsThree" function,
وتواصل الدالة "callAndAdd" وتستدعي الدالة "returnsThree"،
which returns the number three.
والتي تقوم بإرجاع الرقم ثلاثة.
So, all in all, the "callAndAdd" function returns the sum of two and three,
إذن بشكل عام، تقوم الدالة "callAndAdd" بإرجاع مجموع اثنين وثلاثة،
and the result is five.
وتكون النتيجة خمسة.